Emir Mertoğlu

Software Engineer

★ linktr.ee/emirmertoglu

PROFILE

I am an experienced software developer with a passion for creating exceptional digital experiences. With a strong background in engineering and a proven track record of delivering successful projects, I am confident in my ability to contribute to any team. My dedication to quality and staying up-to-date with the latest industry trends ensures that I am always striving to improve and exceed expectations.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, *ERKA Group ⊗*

07/2022 - present

- Documented and tested the components in isolation using Storybook
- Improved performance and SEO with server-side rendering operations using Next.js
- Managed application state with Context API
- Integrated with RESTful APIs using Axios
- Performed general maintenance tasks for the projects such as updating packages, dependencies, and infrastructure and fixing errors and bugs
- Developed responsive HTML emails with MJML and tested them on various email clients
- Used Bitbucket for version control and deployment processes involving Jenkins, Docker, Kubernetes, and other technologies

Intern Software Engineer, *TEKROM Technology ⊗*

02/2022 - 05/2022

- Coded web pages for company projects such as Nildesk Ø, Fig.mobi Ø, Onlivesale Ø, and ConnectProf
 Ø using JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS3
- Used Sass with BEM methodology for meaningful and modular CSS
- Optimized pages to be SEO-friendly and fully responsive across different screen sizes
- Developed responsive HTML emails and tested them on various email clients

Intern Software Engineer, *T-Soft E-Commerce &*

02/2022 - 05/2022

- Contributed to the development of the T-Soft main page and subpages with a new UI design using JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS3
- Used Sass with BEM methodology for meaningful and modular CSS
- Optimized pages to be SEO-friendly and fully responsive across different screen sizes

Intern Software Engineer, Nutima Code *⊘*

03/2021 - 04/2021

- Developed Shopify Details
 Ø browser extension and an npm package called vue-color-picker-basic
 Ø for the company's needs, using Vue.js and JavaScript
- Used Sass with BEM methodology for meaningful and modular CSS

EDUCATION

Information Systems Engineering, Mugla Sitki Kocman University

09/2018 – 06/2022

Graduated as the top-ranking student in both department and faculty, demonstrating exceptional academic performance and dedication.

GPA: 3.63

SKILLS

Next.js
 Redux.js
 Vue.Js

• TypeScript • JavaScript • Node.js • Tailwind CSS

• Material UI • Bootstrap • Sass • Git

ORGANIZATIONS

Google Developer Group (GDG) Mugla, Organizer and Developer ⊗

09/2020 - 03/2021

- Organized and facilitated events on various technical topics
- Developed the GDG&WTM Mugla website using Vue.js and Firebase
- Engaged with local developers and fostered an inclusive environment for tech enthusiasts of all levels

Google Developer Student Clubs (GDSC) MSKU, Core Team Member ⊗

08/2019 - 08/2020

- Coordinated and supported events and initiatives focused on Google developer technologies
- Collaborated with peers to build solutions for local businesses and communities
- Contributed to a peer-to-peer learning environment for students interested in technology

LANGUAGES

English

Turkish